adventuresportsholidays.com 2019-06-21

# AWE365 LTD Privacy Policy

The www.AWE365.com website (the “ **Website** ”) is operated by AWE365 Ltd, company registration number 08449895 at the registered office of 173 Gibbon road, Newhaven, BN9 9ET, United Kingdom. (“ **We** ”, “ **Us** ” or “ **AWE365** ”).

We take your privacy very seriously and we ask that you read this privacy policy carefully as it contains important information on:

  * the personal information we collect about you,
  * what we do with your information, and
  * who your information might be shared with.

## Who we are

For the purposes of the General Data Protection Regulation EU 2016/679 (the “GDPR”), **AWE365** are a “data controller” (i.e. we are responsible for, and control the processing of, your personal information).

## What information we collect?

#### _Personal information provided by you_

We may collect personal information about you (such as your name, address, telephone number, payment card details etc.) when you use our **Website** , register with us or purchase goods or services from us. We may also collect personal information when you contact us, send us feedback or post material to the **Website**.

We may also collect information that your browser sends us whenever you visit our **Website**. This data may include information such as your computer’s IP address, browser type, browser version, the pages of our **Website** that you visit and other statistics relating to your use of the **Website**. This information may be collected in conjunction with third party services such as Google Analytics. However, this information is made anonymous at the point of collection meaning  **you  **cannot personally be identified from it.

#### _Personal information provided by third parties_

We may receive information about you from a third-party source. We will only accept that information if we have evidence that you have consented for the personal information to be passed to us or it is passed pursuant to another legal basis under the GDPR.

#### _Personal information about other individuals_

If you give us information on behalf of someone else, you confirm that the other person has appointed you to act on his/her behalf and has agreed that you can:

  * give consent on his/her behalf to the processing of his/her personal data;
  * receive on his/her behalf any data protection notices; and
  * give consent to the transfer of his/her personal data abroad.

#### _Sensitive personal information_

It is very unlikely that we will ask you to provide sensitive personal information. If we request such information, we will explain why we are requesting it and how we intend to use it.

Sensitive personal information includes information relating to your ethnic origin, your political opinions, your religious beliefs, whether you belong to a trade union, your physical or mental health or condition, your sexual life, and whether you have committed a criminal offence.

We will only collect your sensitive personal information with your explicit consent.

#### _Monitoring and recording communications_

We may monitor and record communications with you (such as telephone conversations and emails) for the purpose of performing the Services we offer to our clients, quality assurance, training, fraud prevention and regulatory compliance.

#### _Use of cookies_

We use cookies on our **Website**. A cookie is a small text file which is placed onto your computer (or other electronic device) when you use our **Website**.

For example, we may monitor how many times you visit the Website, which pages you go to, traffic data, location data and the originating domain name of a user’s internet service provider. This information helps us to build a profile of our users. This data will be aggregated or statistical, which means that, in respect of that data, we will not be able to identify you individually.

You can set your browser not to accept cookies and easily remove cookies from your browser. However, some of our **Website** features may not function as a result. For further information on cookies visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) or [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

## How will we use the information about you?

We collect information about you so that we can:

  * identify you and manage any accounts you hold with us;
  * process your order or carry out obligations arising from any contract(s) entered into between you and us;
  * conduct research, statistical analysis and behavioural analysis;
  * carry out customer profiling and analyse your purchasing preferences;
  * if you agree, let you know about other products or services that may be of interest to you—see ‘Marketing’ section below;
  * detect and prevent fraud;
  * customise our **Website** and its content to your particular preferences;
  * notify you of any changes to our **Website** or to our services that may affect you;
  * carry out security vetting;
  * improve our **Website**  and associated services; and
  * notify you about changes to our services.

#### _Marketing_

Only where you have provided us with specific, informed and unambiguous consent shall we provide you with marketing materials by the mechanism(s) you have consented to (e.g. email). We will only provide you with marketing materials relating to features that you have explicitly consented to.

If you have consented to such receive marketing from us, you can opt out at any time. See ‘What rights do you have?’ below for further information.

#### _Who your information might be shared with_

We may disclose your personal data to:

  * our service providers pursuant to strict data processing agreements that protect your personal data to the same or higher standards than we treat it;
  * law enforcement agencies in connection with any investigation to help prevent unlawful activity; and
  * a court of law or regulator where we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.

Rest assured that we will never pass your information to a third party outside of the categories above without your explicit consent.

#### _Keeping your data secure_

We will use technical and organisational measures to safeguard your personal data, for example:

  * access to your account is controlled by a password and username that are unique to you;
  * we store your personal data on secure servers; and
  * payment details are encrypted using SSL technology (typically you will see a lock icon or green address bar [or both] in your browser when we use this technology).

While we will use all reasonable efforts to safeguard your personal data, you acknowledge that the use of the internet is not entirely secure and for this reason we cannot guarantee the security or integrity of any personal data that are transferred from you or to you via the internet. If you have any particular concerns about your information, please contact us (see ‘How can you contact us?’ below).

Our **Website** may contain links to other websites of our partners, suppliers, advertisers or other approved third parties. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have (or should have) their own privacy policies. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies or the way in which your personal data may be treated by these third parties. We recommend you check the privacy policy of any third party before you submit any personal data to their website.

#### _Transfers of your information out of the EEA_

AWE365  LTD operates within the United Kingdom. We process and store all personal data of our customers on servers located within the European Economic Area (“EEA”).

However, it is possible that we may need to transfer your personal data to countries which are located outside the EEA for the purpose of providing the services to you. Rest assured that any transfer of your personal data outside of the EEA will be subject to a GDPR-compliant guarantee (such as the EU-US Privacy Shield or a Model Contract Clause approved by the European Commission) that will safeguard your privacy rights and give you remedies in the unlikely event of a security breach.

#### _How long do we hold your data for?_

We only keep your personal data as long as necessary for the purpose for which it was obtained. After that period, we either: (1) anonymise the data if we still wish to use it for analytical purposes, or (2) pseudonymise the data if believe in good faith that we may need to process the data in the future for a legitimate purpose, or in all other cases (3) delete it completely from our servers.

## What rights do you have?

#### _Right to request a copy of your information_

You can request a copy of your information which we hold (this is known as a subject access request). If you would like a copy of some or it, please:

  * email or write to us (see ‘How can you contact us?’ below),
  * let us have proof of your identity and address (a copy of your driving licence or passport and a recent utility or credit card bill will suffice), and
  * let us know the information you want a copy of, including any account or reference numbers, if you have them.

We will acknowledge receipt of your request and will respond within thirty (30) days. We will not charge you for providing the information.

#### _Right to correct any mistakes in your information_

You can require us to correct any mistakes in your information which we hold free of charge. If you would like to do this, please:

  * email or write to us (see ‘How can you contact us?’ below),
  * let us have enough information to identify you (e.g. account number, user name, registration details), and
  * let us know the information that is incorrect and what it should be replaced with.

We will acknowledge receipt of your request and will respond within thirty (30) days.

#### _Right to ask us to stop contacting you with direct marketing_

You can ask us to stop contacting you for direct marketing purposes. If you would like to do this, please:

  * click on the ‘unsubscribe’ button at the bottom of marketing emails from us,
  * email or write to us (see ‘How can you contact us?’ below)
  * let us have proof of your identity and address (a copy of your driving licence or passport and a recent utility or credit card bill will suffice), and
  * let us know what method of contact you are not happy with if you are unhappy with certain ways of contacting you only (for example, you may be happy for us to contact you by email but not by telephone).

We will acknowledge receipt of your request and will respond within thirty (30) days.

#### _Right to erasure_

You can request that we delete all personal data relating to you free of charge. If you would like to do this, please:

  * email or write to us (see ‘How can you contact us?’ below), and
  * let us have proof of your identity and address (a copy of your driving licence or passport and a recent utility or credit card bill will suffice), and
  * provide us with the justification for the erasure request (e.g. you are withdrawing your consent, you no longer believe that we should be processing the personal data for the original purpose for which it was obtained, the personal data is being unlawfully processed, there is a legal reason for erasure etc.).

We will acknowledge receipt of your request and will respond within thirty (30) days.

#### _Right to Restrict Processing_

You can request that we restrict processing of some of your personal data. If you would like to do this, please:

  * email or write to us (see ‘How can you contact us?’ below), and
  * let us have proof of your identity and address (a copy of your driving licence or passport and a recent utility or credit card bill will suffice), and
  * provide us with details of what personal data you would like us to restrict the processing of (e.g. where you contest the accuracy of some personal data, we shall restrict the processing of it whilst its accuracy is verified).

We will acknowledge receipt of your request and will respond within thirty (30) days. If we agree to restrict the processing of the personal data before the thirty (30) day period, we will inform you as soon as we have put in place the restriction.

#### _Right to Object_

You can object to us processing any of your personal data. If you would like to do this, please:

  * email or write to us (see ‘How can you contact us?’ below), and
  * let us have proof of your identity and address (a copy of your driving licence or passport and a recent utility or credit card bill will suffice), and
  * provide us with details of what personal data you object to us processing.

We will acknowledge receipt of your request and will respond within thirty (30) days.

#### _Right to Data Portability_

You can request that be provide some or all of your personal data we hold to a third party free of charge. If you would like to do this, please:

  * email, call or write to us (see ‘How can you contact us?’ below),
  * let us have proof of your identity and address (a copy of your driving licence or passport and a recent utility or credit card bill will suffice), and
  * provide us with sufficient details of the third-party entity to which you would like your data transferred.

We will acknowledge receipt of your request and will provide your personal data to the third-party entity in a commonly used machine-readable format within thirty (30) days providing you have provided us with sufficient information to do so. We will not charge you for this service.

#### _Rights relating to automated decision making and profiling_

We use software that automatically processes personal data for us. We ensure that processing using this software is fair and we implement all appropriate technical and organisational measures to ensure inaccuracies are minimised. If you are concerned about the use of such software, you have the right to ask for more details about the processing and request that we stop using the software to process your data. If you would like to do this, please:

  * email, call or write to us (see ‘How can you contact us?’ below),
  * let us have enough information to identify you (e.g. account number, user name, registration details), and
  * provide us with details of your concerns and the categories of personal data you believe are being processed by automated software.

We will acknowledge receipt of your request and will respond within thirty (30) days. Please note that if the automated processing is necessary for the performance of a contract between you and us, if you request that the software is no longer used to process your data, we may not be able to provide you with services any more.

#### _Right to complain to the supervisory authority_

If you are unhappy with the way in which we have dealt with a request you have made or you feel that we are not complying with this Privacy Policy in any way, you have the right to complain to the supervisory authority in the country in which you live. The supervisory authority in England and Wales is the Information Commissioners Office and details of how to contact them are available on their website: [www.ico.org.uk](http://www.ico.org.uk/).

#### _Time Extensions and Refusals_

We reserve the right to extend the time period to respond to any of the requests listed above by up to sixty (60) days where a request is complex or a large number of requests are made. If we fail to respond to you by the deadline we set, you have a right to complain to the supervisory authority or seek a judicial remedy (see – ‘Right to complain to the supervisory authority’ above).

We may also refuse a request where there are legitimate reasons to do so. These include, but are not limited to:

  * where a request is manifestly unfounded, excessive or repetitive; or
  * where personal data is being processed: 
    * in order to comply with a legal obligation;
    * in the public interest;
    * in the exercise or defence of a legal claim;
    * in the exercise of the right to freedom of expression and information.

## How to contact us

Please contact us via info@AWE365.com or write to AWE365 LTD, 173 Gibbon Road, Newhaven, BN9 9ET, UK. If you have any questions about this privacy policy or the information we hold about you, we will be delighted to assist.

## Changes to the privacy policy

This Privacy Policy was last updated in May 2018, however we may change this privacy policy from time to time. You should check this policy occasionally to ensure you are aware of the most recent version that will apply each time you access the **Website**.
